<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
                         
<!ENTITY % base SYSTEM "../docbook/dbgenent.mod">
%base;

<!ENTITY % xinclude SYSTEM "../docbook/xinclude.mod">
%xinclude;

]>
<section id="Conformance">
    <title>Conformance</title>

    <orderedlist>
        <listitem id="DocumentConformance">
            <orderedlist>
                <title> Document Conformance</title>
                <listitem>
                    <para>XLIFF is an XML vocabulary, therefore conformant XLIFF Documents MUST be
                        well formed and valid <olink targetdoc="../xliff22.xml" targetptr="bib_XML"
                            >[XML]</olink> documents.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>

                    <para>Conformant XLIFF documents MUST be valid instances of the official Core
                        XML Schema (<ulink url="&this-loc;/schemas/xliff_core_&version;.xsd"
                            >&this-loc;/schemas/xliff_core_2.2.xsd</ulink>) that is a part of this
                        multipart Work Product.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>

                    <para> As not all aspects of the XLIFF specification can be expressed in terms
                        of XML Schemas, conformant XLIFF documents MUST also comply with all
                        relevant elements and attributes definitions, normative usage descriptions,
                        and Constraints specified in this specification document.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>XLIFF documents MAY contain custom extensions, as defined in the <olink
                            targetdoc="../extensions/extensions.xml" targetptr="extensions"
                            >Extension Mechanisms</olink> section. </para>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
        </listitem>
        <listitem id="ApplicationConformance">
            <orderedlist>
                <title> Application Conformance</title>
                <listitem>
                    <para>XLIFF Writers MUST create conformant XLIFF Documents to be considered
                        XLIFF compliant.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para> Agents processing conformant XLIFF Documents that contain custom
                        extensions are not REQUIRED to understand and process non-XLIFF elements or
                        attributes. However, conformant applications SHOULD preserve existing custom
                        extensions when processing conformant XLIFF documents, provided that the
                        elements that contain custom extensions are not removed according to XLIFF
                        Processing Requirements or the extension's own processing
                        requirements.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>All Agents MUST comply with Processing Requirements for otherwise
                        unspecified Agents or without a specifically set target Agent.</para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                    <para> Specialized Agents defined in this specification - this is Extractor,
                        Merger, Writer, Modifier, and Enricher Agents - MUST comply with the
                        Processing Requirements targeting their specifically defined type of Agent
                        on top of Processing Requirements targeting all Agents as per point c.
                        above.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>XLIFF is a format explicitly designed for exchanging data among various
                        Agents. Thus, a conformant XLIFF application MUST be able to accept XLIFF
                        Documents it had written after those XLIFF Documents were Modified or
                        Enriched by a different application, provided that:</para>
                    <orderedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>The processed files are conformant XLIFF Documents,</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>in a state compliant with all relevant Processing
                                Requirements.</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </orderedlist>

                </listitem>


            </orderedlist>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <orderedlist>
                <title> Backwards Compatibility</title>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Conformant applications are REQUIRED to support XLIFF 2.0, 2.1 and 2.2.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Conformant applications are NOT REQUIRED to support XLIFF 1.2 or previous
                        versions. </para>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
        </listitem>
    </orderedlist>

    <note>
        <para>XLIFF documents conformant to this specification are not and cannot be conformant to
            XLIFF 1.2 or earlier versions. If an application needs to support for whatever business
            reason both XLIFF 2.x and XLIFF 1.2 or earlier, these will need to be supported as
            separate functionalities. </para>
    </note>
</section>
