<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
                         
<!ENTITY % base SYSTEM "../docbook/dbgenent.mod">
%base;

<!ENTITY % xinclude SYSTEM "../docbook/xinclude.mod">
%xinclude;

]>
<section>
  <title>Introduction</title>

  <para>XLIFF is the <emphasis>XML Localization Interchange File Format</emphasis> designed by a
    group of multilingual content publishers, software providers, localization service providers,
    localization tools providers, and researchers. It is intended to give any multilingual content
    owner a single interchange file format that can be understood by any localization provider,
    using any conformant localization tool. While the primary focus is on being a lossless
    interchange format, usage of XLIFF as a processing format is neither encouraged nor discouraged
    or prohibited.</para>

  <para><emphasis>All text is normative unless otherwise labeled.</emphasis>
  </para>

  <section id="newSinceLast">
    <title>Changes from earlier Versions</title>
    <para>XLIFF 2.2 has two main significant differences from the previous version published (XLIFF
      2.1):</para>

    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para> XLIFF 2.2 is presented in two separate documents:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis>XLIFF Version 2.2. Part 1: Core</emphasis> presents the XLIFF core,
              which is the minimum set of XML elements and attributes required to create a valid
              XLIFF file.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis>XLIFF Version 2.2. Part 2: Extended</emphasis> presents the XLIFF core as
              well as the optional modules that were created to store information about specific
              processes. For example, the <olink targetdoc="../modules/candidates/specification.xml"
                targetptr="candidates">Translation Candidates Module</olink> was designed to store
              translation suggestions and their associated metadata.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>In previous versions of XLIFF, the specification was always presented in a single
          document. This change in the presentation mode was introduced to produce a simplified
          version (<emphasis>Part 1: Core</emphasis>) of the specification that would be easier to
          use, especially for those agents who are not interested in implementing the optional
          modules.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>XLIFF 2.2 includes the new <olink
            targetdoc="../modules/plural_gender_select/specification.xml"
            targetptr="plural_gender_select_module">Plural, Gender, and Select Module</olink>, which
          was designed to store information needed to represent and process messages with variants.
          The new module description can be found in the document XLIFF Version 2.2. Part 2:
          Extended.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>For a detailed list of changes made between version 2.1 and the current version (2.2)
      please see the <olink targetdoc="../appendices/changeTracking.xml"
        targetptr="specChangeTracking">Specification Change Tracking</olink> section in Appendix
      D.</para>
    <para>Note that all changes introduced in version 2.2 were designed to maintain compatibility
      with versions 2.0 and 2.1.</para>
  </section>

  <section id="definitions">
    <title>Definition of terms</title>

    <variablelist>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Agent</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>any application or tool that generates (creates), reads, edits, writes, processes,
            stores, renders or otherwise handles XLIFF documents.</para>
          <para>Agent is the most general application conformance target that subsumes all other
            specialized user agents disregarding whether they are defined in this specification or
            not.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Enrich</term>
        <term>Enriching</term>
        <listitem>
          <para> the process of associating module and extension based metadata and resources with
            the Extracted XLIFF payload </para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <title>Processing Requirements</title>
            <listitem>
              <para>Enriching MAY happen at the time of Extraction. </para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
          <note>
            <para>Extractor knowledge of the native format is not assumed while Enriching.</para>
          </note>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Enricher</term>
        <term>Enricher Agent</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>any Agent that performs the Enriching process </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Extract</term>
        <term>Extraction</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>the process of encoding localizable content from a native content or User Interface
            format as XLIFF payload, so that localizable parts of the content in the source language
            are available for translation into the target language along with the necessary context
            information </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Extractor</term>
        <term>Extractor Agent</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>any Agent that performs the Extraction process </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Merge</term>
        <term>Merging</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>the process of importing XLIFF payload back to the originating native format, based
            on the <emphasis>full knowledge</emphasis> of the Extraction mechanism, so that the
            localized content or User Interface strings replace the source language in the native
            format </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Merger</term>
        <term>Merger Agent</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>an Agent that performs the Merge process </para>

          <warning>
            <para> Unless specified otherwise, any Merger is deemed to have the same knowledge of
              the native format as the Extractor throughout the specification. </para>
            <para>Mergers independent of Extractors can succeed, but it is out of scope of this
              specification to specify interoperability for merging back without the full Extractor
              knowledge of the native format. </para>
          </warning>
        </listitem>

      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Modify</term>
        <term>Modification</term>
        <listitem>
          <para> the process of changing core and module XLIFF structural and inline elements that
            were previously created by other Writers </para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <title>Processing Requirements</title>
            <listitem>
              <para> XLIFF elements MAY be Modified and Enriched at the same time. </para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
          <note>
            <para>Extractor or Enricher knowledge of the native format is not assumed while
              modifying.</para>
          </note>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Modifier</term>
        <term>Modifier Agent</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>an Agent that performs the Modification process </para>

        </listitem>

      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Translation</term>
        <term>Translate</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>a rendering of the meaning of the source text, expressed in the target
            language</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>Writer</term>
        <term>Writer Agent</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>an Agent that creates, generates, or otherwise writes an XLIFF document for whatever
            purpose, including but not limited to Extractor, Modifier, and Enricher Agents. </para>

          <note>
            <para> Since XLIFF is intended as an exchange format rather than a processing format,
              many applications will need to generate XLIFF documents from their internal processing
              formats, even in cases when they are processing XLIFF documents created by another
              Extractor. </para>
          </note>
        </listitem>


      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </section>

  <section id="keyconcepts">
    <title>Key concepts</title>

    <variablelist>
      <varlistentry>
        <term>XLIFF Core</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>The core of XLIFF &version; consists of the minimum set of XML elements and
            attributes required to (a) prepare a document that contains text extracted from one or
            more files for localization, (b) allow it to be completed with the translation of the
            extracted text, and (c) allow the generation of translated versions of the original
            document.</para>

          <para>The XML namespace that corresponds to the core subset of XLIFF &version; is
              <code>"urn:oasis:names:tc:xliff:document:&version;"</code>.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>XLIFF-defined (elements and attributes)</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>The following is the list of allowed schema URI prefixes for XLIFF-defined elements
            and attributes:</para>
          <simplelist>
            <member><code>urn:oasis:names:tc:xliff:</code></member>
            <member><code>http://www.w3.org/2005/11/its</code></member>
          </simplelist>

          <para>However, the following namespaces are NOT considered XLIFF-defined for the purposes
            of the XLIFF &version; specification:</para>
          <simplelist>
            <member><code>urn:oasis:names:tc:xliff:document:1.0</code></member>
            <member><code>urn:oasis:names:tc:xliff:document:1.1</code></member>
            <member><code>urn:oasis:names:tc:xliff:document:1.2</code></member>
          </simplelist>
          <para>Elements and attributes from other namespaces are not XLIFF-defined.</para>
        </listitem>


      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>XLIFF Document</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>Any XML document that declares the namespace
              <code>"urn:oasis:names:tc:xliff:document:&version;"</code> as its main namespace, has
              <olink targetdoc="elements/structural/xliff.xml" targetptr="xliff"
                ><code>&lt;xliff></code></olink> as the root element and complies with the XML
            Schemas and the declared Constraints that are part of this specification.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
        <term>XLIFF Module</term>

        <listitem>
          <para>A module is an OPTIONAL set of XML elements and attributes that stores information
            about a process applied to an XLIFF Document and the data incorporated into the document
            as result of that process.</para>

          <para>Each official module defined for XLIFF &version; has its grammar defined in an
            independent XML Schema with a separate namespace.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  </section>


</section>
