<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"[
<!ENTITY % xinclude SYSTEM "../docbook/xinclude.mod">
%xinclude;
<!ENTITY % local.common.attrib "xml:base CDATA #IMPLIED">
<!--the document properties were transferred to "dockbook/dbgenent.mod"-->
]>
<section id="ChangeTrackWRT20">
<title>High Level Summary of Changes made in Comparison to XLIFF Version &pversion;</title>
<para>This is to facilitate human tracking of changes between XLIFF Versions &version; and &pversion;. </para>
   
   
   <orderedlist>
      <!-- Add new change track items to the bottom of the list -->
      <listitem>
         <para>Two major features are being added in XLIFF Version &version;:</para>
         <orderedlist>
            <listitem>
               <para>Advanced Validation methods</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
               <para>Native Support for ITS 2.0</para>
            </listitem>
         </orderedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
         <para>The Change Tracking Module was demoted to an extension to free hands of the TC and
            other implementers while working on a new version of the Change Tracking Module for
            XLIFF 2.2.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
         <para>A major bug fix was performed on the core xsd. The core xsd now enforces the
               <code>xs:language</code> data type on the <code>srcLang</code> and
               <code>trgLang</code> attributes. It was critical to make this fix, because -- as per
            OASIS policy -- validation artifacts would prevail over the prose provisions that are
            correct in both XLIFF &version; and XLIFF &pversion;.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
         <para>Also an erroneously omitted Constraint of the <olink
               targetdoc="../attributes/xml_lang.xml" targetptr="xml_lang"
               ><code>xml:lang</code></olink> attribute on the <olink targetptr="source"
               targetdoc="../elements/structural/source.xml"><code>&lt;source></code></olink>
            element has been added/restored in the normative text.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
         <para>Apart from the five (5) major changes mentioned above, numerous editorial bugfixes
            were made to secure greater clarity, either by fixing example errors or omissions, or by
            reorganizing normative content, so that the intent becomes clear and unequivocal at some
            troublesome places highlighted by XLIFF &pversion; implementers. </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
         <para>Importantly, the TC decided to drop informative listings of the validation artifacts
            that had bloated the spec extent unnecessarily, were hard to keep in sync with the
            actual normative artifacts, while their actual usability proved rather limited --
            readers who were able to read schema languages would not actually read them as printed
            listings and would anyways refer to the actual validation artifacts that are now
            referenced more prominently.</para>
      </listitem>
      
      
   
      
      <!-- Add new change track items to the bottom of the list
<listitem>
<para>[This is a suggested wording for your change track item:] In response to comment(s) nnn, nnn, and nnn, following changes have been made to
feature XYZ: [description of changes]... </para>
</listitem>
-->
      
   </orderedlist>
   <para>In spite of the above mentioned changes, fixes, clarifications, and additions, the
      practical workings of the <firstterm>XLIFF Core</firstterm> hasn't been affected and none of
      the changes (except the bugfixes under 3 and 4) have affected the core namespace
         <code>"urn:oasis:names:tc:xliff:document:&bschversion;"</code> or the <firstterm>XLIFF
         Core</firstterm>
      <olink targetdoc="../xliff21.xml" targetptr="XMLSchema">[XML Schema]</olink>, <ulink
         url="&this-loc;/schemas/xliff_core_&bschversion;.xsd"
         >&this-loc;/schemas/xliff_core_&bschversion;.xsd</ulink> that expresses its basic grammar
      and structure.</para>
</section>
